FONYUY BORIS LAMI

(+250) 785 539 428 | fborisla@andrew.cmu.edu live:fonyuyborislami | linkedin.com/in/f-boris Kigali, Rwanda

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data scientist with over 1 year of experience in applying engineering principles in the IT industry. Combine intercultural competence with interpersonal and technical skills to achieve objectives. Part of winning team in the hackathon "CMU-Africa: Fighting Fire with Data" on Zindi's platform in 2020. Seeking an internship opportunity to apply emerging data science knowledge and skills while building experience in real-world projects as a data scientist.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEER

12/2019 - 07/2020

Wiicom, Nkoabang | Yaounde | Centre | Cameroon



- Elaborated configuration template files for routers that were tested and validated in a virtual environment in view of the implementation of the MPLS Core Network of WIICOM SARL.
- Wrote and deployed a C++ program that registers the entry and exit time of personnel in a MySQL database from a Dahua Access Control which significantly increased personnel's punctuality.

COMPUTER SCIENCE RESEARCHER TRAINEE

04/2019 - 09/2019

SAMOVAR UMR 5157, TELECOM SUDPARIS, IMT | Evry | France

- TELECOM SudParis
- 三級暴險
- Implemented the connection of SPASEQ to ingest multiple real streams of RDF graph events with the use of TripleWave for the transformation of non-RDF streams to RDF streams serialized in N-Triples.
- Extended SPASEQ to evaluate a single graph pattern over multiple RDF graph streams for the fusion of RDF data streams.
- Elaborated NTIMES pattern matching for RDF data fusion.

EDUCATION



Master of Science in Information Technology Carnegie Mellon University Africa

Specialization: Applied Machine Learning

Cumulative GPA of 3.56



Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering 2014 – 2019 National Advanced School of Engineering Yaounde, Cameroon

- Thesis: "Formal Approach for the Fusion of Resource Description Framework (RDF) data streams"
- Cumulative GPA of 3.64
- I graduated top of my class Telecommunications Engineering 2019 batch

SKILLS

- Public speaking
- Strong interpersonal skills
- Good verbal communication skills
- Quick learner
- Collaboration skills
- Adaptability skills
- Problem-solving skills

- Python (intermediate)
- Tableau (intermediate)
- MySQL (basic)
- MATLAB (intermediate)
- Microsoft Excel (intermediate)
- Java (intermediate)
- C/C++ (intermediate)

LANGUAGES \Diamond

English: Native speaker.

• French: Fluent.

INTERESTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won 1st place out of 19 in the hackathon at CMU-Africa: Fighting Fire with Data 2020.
- Won 2nd place out of 123 in the hackathon AIMS Data Science Hackathon by Microsoft aimed at predicting wealth index in African countries.
- MasterCard Foundation scholar representative for CMU Africa, 2021.
- Tutored college students in Physics, Pure Mathematics and Further Mathematics and participating in a mentorship project for mentoring STEM students.
- MasterCard Foundation full scholarship award, CMU-Africa.
- Mentor at MasterCard Foundation CMU Africa mentorship program 2021.

2020 - 2022